We should probably go over how to represent an HMM.
我们应该复习如何表示一个隐马尔可夫模型
&gt;&gt; Right, the Russell and Norvig book draws them like a Markov chain and
— 没错 罗素 (Russell ) 和诺维格 (Norvig) 的书中把他们描述成马尔可夫链
adds an output node for each state.
然后为每个状态增加了输出节点
In this representation, which is common in the machine learning community,
这种表现方法在机器学习业界很常见
each Xi represents a frame of data.
其中每个 Xi 表示一个数据帧
Xo is the beginning state which is useful for keeping data.
X0 是初始状态 用于保留数据
X1 represents the first time frame t equals 1.
X1 代表第一次帧 t 等于 1
E1 represents the output at that time.
E1 表示当时的输出
X2 is the next time frame and E2 is the output at that time.
X2 是下一次帧 E2 是当时的输出
And so on, until we get to the end of the sequence.
等等 直到我们进行到序列的结尾
The HMM states are implicit in this representation.
在这种表现手法中 隐马尔可夫模型状态是隐含的
However, I find it easier to think of HMMs in terms of their states.
不过我发现很容易根据它们的状态联想到隐马尔可夫模型
So I'm going to deviate from the book and
那么我要脱离这本书
use a representation that is more specific to HMMs for this discussion.
使用这个讨论中隐马尔可夫模型更具体的表现方法
To get things started let's imagine we have a signal through time that looks
首先假设我们有通过时间的信号
like this graph.
像这个图中这样
At t equals 0, its value is -2.
t 等于 0 时 它的值是 -2
By t equals 10 it is at -1, by t equals 15, it's at 0.
t 等于 10 时 它的值是 -1 t 等于 15 时 它的值是 0
And at t equals 35 it's at 1, at t equals 38 it's at 2.
t 等于 35 时 它的值是 1 t 等于 38 时 它的值是 2
&gt;&gt; So it looks like the graph is made up of 4 different parts.
— 这个图由 4 个不同部分组成
&gt;&gt; That's right, we're going to use a 4 state HMM to represent it.
— 没错 我们要使用 4 个隐马尔可夫模型进行表示
We are trying to design a model that could have generated this data.
我们尝试设计一个模型 可以产生这些数据
In this case we are going to use a left-to-right HMM,
在这个例子中 我们使用从左到右的隐马尔可夫模型
meaning that we never transition back to a previous state once we've left it.
说明我们一旦离开之前的状态 就无法回到之前状态
These loops are called self transitions, which indicates that the model can stay
这些循环称为自转换 表明模型可以在
in the same state for several timeframes.
多个时间帧中维持相同状态
&gt;&gt; Next we need to figure out the emission probabilities.
— 接下来我们要计算发射概率
&gt;&gt; I like to call them alpha probabilities, but
— 我喜欢称它们是 α 概率
it's just a different name for them.
但这只是它们不同的名字而已
All it means is which values that are allowable while we are in a given state.
它表示我们在给定的状态中 哪些值是容许的
&gt;&gt; It's a little bit more subtle than that, right?
— 这有些更加微妙 对吧？
Since the output distributions are densities,
由于输出分布是密度
these are not really probabilities.
这些不是真正的概率
&gt;&gt; But it's a convenient fiction for our discussion, so
— 这是我们讨论中方便的假定
I'm going to stay with it.
所以我会保留它
In this case, creating the output probabilities is easy.
在这个例子中 创建输出概率很简单
The first part of the graph is from -2 to -1.
图表的第一部分是从 -2 到 -1
&gt;&gt; And all values are equally represented, so
— 所有值得到同等体现
we can just use a box car distribution.
所以我们只使用一个脉冲分布
&gt;&gt; Great,
— 非常棒
for state two the upper distribution is going to be a box car from -1 to 0.
在状态 2 中 上面的分布是像是从 -1 到 0 到脉冲
&gt;&gt; In state 3, we have a box starting from 0 to 1, and state 4 is from 1 to 2.
— 在状态 3 中 我们有个从 0 到 1 的脉冲 在状态 4 中是从 1 到 2 的脉冲
&gt;&gt; Now we need to figure out the values for the transition probabilities.
— 现在我们需要计算转移概率的值
Let's look at the first part of the graph again.
我们再看一下图表的第一部分
We spend about 10 time frames in the first part of the graph
我们在图表的第一部分中花费 10 帧
before we transition to the second part of the graph.
然后转换到图表的第二部分
So we want to assign an appropriate probability here
那么我们想在这里赋予合适的概率
where we escape state 1.
这里避开了状态 1
&gt;&gt; Well, that seems of one off, let's assign a probability of 0.1.
— 这里不再是 1 我们赋予概率 0.1
That way on average we expect to stay in that state for 10 frames.
我们希望停留在这个状态 10 帧
&gt;&gt; Since all the probabilities out of a state have to sum to 1, and we only have
— 既然一个状态所有概率总和为 1 我们只剩下
the self-transistion probability left, we know that it has to be 0.9.
自转换概率 我们知道这是 0.9
&gt;&gt; And here's a little trick, if we want to know the number of time frames we
— 如果我们想知道停留在既定状态的时间帧
expect to stay in a given state.
这里有个小技巧
We can just use the formula,
我们可以只使用公式
1 over 1- the self-transition probability, to figure it out.
1 除以 1 减去自转换概率 即 1/(1-p) 进行计算
&gt;&gt; Thanks, for
— 谢谢 因为某些原因
some reason, I keep forgetting to use that trick when I'm working on more
我在使用更复杂的隐马尔可夫模型时 其中包含大量状态变化
complex HMMs where there are a lot of transitions out of the state.
忘记使用这个技巧
&gt;&gt; We can continue this process for each of the states, state 2 has 5 frames.
— 我们可以对每个状态继续这个过程 状态 2 包括 5 个时间帧
So we'll make this output probability one-fifth or 0.2 and
我们得到这个输出概率是五分之一 即 0.2
this one four-fifth or 0.8.
这个是五分之四 即 0.8
State 3 has 20 frames, so this arrow gets a one-twentieth,
状态 3 包括 20 个时间帧 所以这里得到二十分之一
or a 0.05 and this is 0.95.
即 0.05 这里是 0.95
And the last transition out of the model is one-third, or 0.33,
模型中的最后一个转换是三分之一 即 0.33
with the cell's transition being 0.67.
这个框的转变是 0.67
&gt;&gt; Hold it, I just realized something, you said I could figure out how many
— 等一下 我意识到一件事 你说过我可以
frames I expect to be in the state by using the formula,
使用公式 1/(1-p)
1 over 1- the self-transition probability.
计算状态中的帧数
But if I set the probability to 0, I get 1 over 1-0, which equals 1.
但是如果我设置概率为 0 计算 1/(1-0) 等于 1
That means I'll get at least 1 output from that state.
这意味着我从状态中得到至少 1 个输出
&gt;&gt; But that's fine, we output as soon as enter the state from the previous state,
— 不过那是对的 我们一旦从之前的状态进入这个状态 得到输出
and then we transition to the next state.
然后转移到下一个状态
&gt;&gt; Hm, okay, that explains something else to me.
— 好 这向我解释了其他事情
A lot of manuals and toolkits post dummy state at the beginning of each model.
许多手册和工具包在每个模型的开头提出了虚拟状态
I guess to explicitly represent entering the first state.
我想可以清晰展现进入第一个状态
Actually that leads me to another point.
实际上这让我想到另一点
When I'm being more formal, I just put the arrow at the first state.
当我处于更加形式化时 我把箭头指向第一个状态
If we can enter the model at several different positions with equal
如果我们进入相同概率的多个不同位置
probability, I put these arrows at each potential point of entry.
我把这些箭头指向每个潜在的输入点
If the entry points have different probabilities,
如果输入点有不同的概率
I'd write them at these arrows.
我会把它们写在这些箭头上
&gt;&gt; There are more details we will cover later, but
— 我们之后还会学习更多细节
we have shown what we need to create an HMM by inspection
不过我们已经说明了通过检查创建隐马尔可夫模型
to represent a given signal &gt;&gt; In practice,
表现特定信号需要做什么
we expect to have lots of examples of a signal we want to model.
— 实际上我们需要有想要模拟的大量信号示例
And we'll have to create a model that can accommodate all of the different
我们会创建模型 包含所有不同的例子
examples, balancing both generalization and overfitting.
平衡泛化和过度拟合
But that will come later, for
不过这是后面的内容
now, we will assume that we can create an HMM by inspection.
现在我们会假设通过创建隐马尔可夫模型
In fact, the technique is robust enough that inspection will work for
实际上这种技巧在检查问题第一关时
a first pass at a problem.
非常强大
&gt;&gt; How about we move on to a real problem?
— 我们用来解决实际问题会怎么样？
&gt;&gt; Sounds like a good idea.
— 听起来是不错的想法